vsl.co.at 2019-04-08

# Vienna Symphonic Library

Your privacy is important to us! Vienna Symphonic Library GmbH cares about the protection of your personalized data. This privacy statement explains which information is being collected and processed.

### 1\. General

Personalized data and information about ordered and registered products are carefully handled according to the provisions of the Austrian Federal Data Protection Act. The following statement only refers to the Vienna Symphonic Library website and other communication with VSL, such as e-mail and phone.

### 2\. Anonymous Data Collection

When you visit our website the following information will be collected:

  * Domain name
  * Browser type and version
  * Operating system
  * Referring site
  * Website you are visiting
  * Date and time of your access
  * IP address

Anonymous information is separated from personalized data (see section 5) to prevent identification of personal information relating to any one individual. VSL uses this statistically evaluated information to improve the functionality and quality of the website. User data is made available to agents using our Order Interface.

### 3\. Cookies

Cookies are small text files placed on your device to identify returning users. It allows us to customize our website to your preferences and settings and to analyse the performance of our website and online services. Cookie data remain on your local computer and are not stored by Vienna Symphonic Library. Most browsers accept cookies automatically, but you can delete and disable cookies using the privacy settings of your browser. Please be aware that by blocking cookies you may not be able to use the full functionality of our website, therefore we recommend leaving the cookie function on.

### 4\. Tracking with Google Analytics

Vienna Symphonic Library uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Inc., to evaluate user behaviour. Information generated by cookies (see section 3) about your use of the website will be transmitted to Google and stored on servers in the United States of America.  
Google will use this data for the purpose of compiling reports on website activity for VSL and providing other services relating to Internet usage and online activity. This information may be also transferred by Google to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. By using our website you agree to the processing of your data by Google in the manner and for the purpose described above.

### 5\. Use of Hotjar for Web Analysis

On its website Vienna Symphonic Library uses the web analysing service Hotjar by Hotjar, Ltd. ([www.hotjar.com](http://www.hotjar.com/)). This tool places the following cookies on your computer and retrieves them: _hjUserId comprises a universally unique identifier (UUID) that allows us to identify your visits on different pages and in various sessions.   
The cookie information is regularly transferred to a server by Hotjar Ltd. in Ireland and stored there. You can prevent the storage of information in cookies using the privacy settings of your browser. If you do so, please note that it is possible that you may not be able to use the full functionality of our website. You have the option to prevent Hotjar from collecting information about your usage of our website by adding a “do not track” header to your browser. Here’s where you can learn how to do that: <https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out>.

### 6\. Facebook Remarketing

This website uses the remarketing function “Custom Audiences” by Facebook, Inc. (“Facebook”). This function allows visitors of our website to be presented with interest-based advertisements (“Facebook ads”) when they’re visiting the social network Facebook. In order to do this, the remarketing tag by Facebook was implemented on our website. This tag establishes a connection to Facebook’s servers and transfers the information that you have visited our website and allocates it to your personal Facebook user account. You will find more information on how Facebook collects and uses data as well as about your rights and possibilities to protect your privacy in Facebook’s privacy statement at <https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy>. As an alternative, you can deactivate the remarketing function “Custom Audiences” at <https://www.facebook.com/settings/?tab=ads#_=_>. You need to be logged in at Facebook in order to do so.

### 7\. Personal Data

Vienna Symphonic Library will use the collected personal data to improve and personalize your experiences and to provide you with the products we offer. There are a variety of situations in which we may save personal information, such as when you register as a customer, subscribe to our newsletter, or purchase or register one of our products. We collect and store your personal data solely for the purpose of processing your messages or inquiries and for closing contracts. Data is collected when you open a user account, take part in the VSL community, subscribe to our newsletter, purchase or register Vienna Symphonic Library’s products or get in contact with us using another channel, e.g., e-mail. We only collect, store and process your personal data for fulfilling the contract and not for other purposes. In this context we may transmit certain information to commissioned third parties such as distributors or suppliers if necessary to fulfil the contract. These partners also maintain the same privacy statement. No personal data will be distributed to third parties who are not involved in the contractual business process. We will only contact you based on the stored data if you have given your explicit consent to do so (e.g., subscription to our newsletter).

The following data are collected: Salutation, name, company, address, e-mail, phone, website, fax, profession, bank details, credit card number, PayPal account, VAT-ID, optional billing or delivery address, forum name, preferred language and information about ordered and registered products. While you’re visiting our web shop pages, an AuthCookie and a Session Cookie are placed on your computer. We might send out a questionnaire without your consent to survey customer satisfaction.

### 8\. Transfer of Data to Non-EU Third-Party Countries to Fulfil a Contract

On § 12 Datenschutzgesetz (Data Protection Regulation): There is either a resolution of adequacy by the European Commission (currently covering Andorra, Argentina, Faroe Islands, Guernsey, Isle of Man, Israel, Jersey, Canada, New Zealand, Switzerland, Uruguay and the USA by the EU-US Privacy Shield) or another exception applies, such as § 12 Abs 2 Z 6 DSG covering the case that a contract can only be fulfilled by transferring customer data to third countries. For a list of Authorized Dealers and Distributors please refer to the following links:  
<https://www.vsl.co.at/en/Where_to_Buy/Authorized_Dealers>  
<https://www.vsl.co.at/en/Where_to_Buy/International_Distributors>

### 9\. Deletion of Your Data

Your user data will be stored as long as you are a registered licensee of any of our products. Registered users without a license may request the deletion of their data at any time. In this case, your Forum NickName remains visible or can be replaced by “Anonymous”. Postings that quote your original posting and nickname won’t be affected by the change, as is information stored in our ticketing system from communication with you, e.g., via email to our sales and support team.

### 10\. Data Protection

By using technical measures such as authentication and authorization procedures we maintain a high level of security in order to protect your personal data from manipulation, loss, destruction or access by unauthorized persons. Vienna Symphonic Library continually improves your data protection by implementing current technical developments. If you are logged in at Vienna Symphonic Library’s web shop, you will be automatically logged out after 30 minutes of inactivity. We cannot guarantee full data security of e-mail messages, therefore we recommend encrypting confidential information (e.g., credit card number) in a zip-file or sending it as a registered letter.

Help us to improve the security of your personal data, for example by taking special care of your passwords and by not passing them on to third parties. In no event will a Vienna Symphonic Library employee contact you to ask for your password.

### 11\. Information About Saved Data

In accordance with prevailing data protection regulations you have the right to request a copy of the personalized information we hold about you. You may correct, disable or delete your personal data at any time. Please use this email address for requests and applications: [support@vsl.co.at](mailto:support@vsl.co.at "VSL Support")  
For complaints please refer to Österreichische Datenschutzbehörde, Hohenstaufengasse 3, 1010 Wien ([dsb@dsb.gv.at](mailto:dsb@dsb.gv.at)).

### 12\. Newsletter

If you subscribed to a newsletter on our website, you will receive e-mails from the Vienna Symphonic Library at regular intervals. You can unsubscribe from receiving newsletters at any time.

### 13\. Declaration of Consent

You confirm that the entry of your personal information (e.g., e-mail address, name, address) on our website is explicitly voluntary. We do not collect, process, or use your data without your explicit consent. You may revoke your consent at any time.
